<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>community on yt project blog</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/tags/community/</link><description>Recent content in community on yt project blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 15:57:41 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A short update about the yt user's meeting</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/2020usersmeeting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 15:57:41 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/2020usersmeeting/</guid><description>&lt;p>A short post about the yt users meeting so far!!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Much Ado About Governance</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/governance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 16:19:10 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/governance/</guid><description>&lt;p>A new post about our project&amp;rsquo;s governance!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Relicensing yt from GPLv3 to BSD</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/relicensing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 16:36:29 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/relicensing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our reasoning for switching licenses for the yt-project&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The first yt development workshop!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/devworkshop2013/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 17:04:06 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/devworkshop2013/</guid><description>&lt;p>On March 6-8, 2013 we held a yt development workshop at UCSC. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about
it!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Announcing the 2013 yt development workshop</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/devworkshopannounce2013/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 13:24:33 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/devworkshopannounce2013/</guid><description>&lt;p>Announcing the 2013 yt developer workshop!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>yt Google+ Hangout tomorrow!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_42_yt-google-hangout-tomorrow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 04:42:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_42_yt-google-hangout-tomorrow/</guid><description>Tomorrow we&amp;rsquo;re going to try something new &amp;ndash; Google Hangouts! If you&amp;rsquo;d like help with something, to share some feedback, or just to say hi to other community members, stop by Tuesday, May 1st. We&amp;rsquo;ll be starting up around 2PM Eastern and continuing for a couple hours.
If this works out, we&amp;rsquo;ll try it again from time to time, to catch up on new developments, help out with scripts or visualization issues, soliciting feedback, and to chat about using and developing yt.</description></item><item><title>What's new with yt?</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_41_what-s-new-with-yt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 03:10:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_41_what-s-new-with-yt/</guid><description>Now that the post-workshop preparations and work have settled down, I thought it might be interesting to share some of the developments going on with yt. We&amp;rsquo;re still a long way from a new release, so these interim &amp;lsquo;development&amp;rsquo; updates are meant to be a bit of a teaser. As always, these features are either in the main branch or (if noted) in a public fork on BitBucket. If they sound interesting, drop us a line on `yt-dev &amp;lt;http://lists.</description></item><item><title>yt workshop 2012 - a success!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_40_yt-workshop-2012-a-success/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 09:02:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_40_yt-workshop-2012-a-success/</guid><description>The yt workshop last week in Chicago ( http://yt-project.org/workshop2012/ ) was an enormous success. On behalf of the organizing and technical committees, I&amp;rsquo;d like to specifically thank the FLASH Center, particularly Don Lamb, Mila Kuntu, Carrie Eder, for their hospitality; the venue was outstanding and their hospitality touching. Additionally, we&amp;rsquo;re very grateful to the Adler Planetarium&amp;rsquo;s Doug Roberts and Mark SubbaRao for hosting us on Wednesday evening &amp;ndash; seeing the planetarium show as well as volume renderings made by yt users up on the dome was so much fun.</description></item><item><title>Workshop in just a week!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_39_workshop-in-just-a-week/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 18:45:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_39_workshop-in-just-a-week/</guid><description>The first yt workshop is in just about a week. We&amp;rsquo;ve updated the website with the current list of talks, along with information about getting to and from the workshop from the conference hotel, and information about how to get the sample data. Keep your eyes on the website in the lead up to the workshop, as we&amp;rsquo;ll be posting a script for fisheye lens renderings for our viz night at the Adler, information about the talks and example scripts, and other useful info.</description></item><item><title>yt workshop registration is open!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_37_yt-workshop-registration-is-open/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 13:17:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_37_yt-workshop-registration-is-open/</guid><description>Registration for the 2012 yt workshop, to be held at the FLASH center in Chicago from January 24-26, is now open.
Please register here: http://yt- project.org/workshop2012/</description></item><item><title>Google+ Page for yt</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_35_google-page-for-yt/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 03:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_35_google-page-for-yt/</guid><description>yt now has a Google Plus page. Here&amp;rsquo;s we&amp;rsquo;ll post smaller, less blog-worthy items, hold video conferencing &amp;lsquo;hangouts&amp;rsquo;, and so on. Encircle away! And if you post something you&amp;rsquo;d like to be reshared, just be sure to explicitly share it with &amp;lsquo;+yt&amp;rsquo; so we know.</description></item><item><title>Announcing the 2012 yt Workshop</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_33_announcing-the-2012-yt-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 17:24:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_33_announcing-the-2012-yt-workshop/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to announce the 2012 yt Workshop at the FLASH Center in Chicago, January 24-26.
The workshop will be aimed at both users and developers of yt. We will begin with intensive user training, moving from basic usage to advanced and parallel usage. Users are encouraged to bring their ideas and prototypes for new analysis routines as there will be opportunities to work with more experienced developers. We will then address to how to modify, extend and contribute to yt, and transition to a developers workshop.</description></item><item><title>New Screencasts</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_32_new-screencasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 12:20:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_32_new-screencasts/</guid><description>A few of the yt developers have been experimenting with screencasts to show off new features or demonstrate how to do some things. Sam and I have both prepared screencasts on volume rendering and getting started with developing, respectively. Check them out below, and please feel free to leave comments and let us know what you think &amp;ndash; not just about the screencasts, but about what they demonstrate, and if you think any of the concepts or routines could be made easier.</description></item><item><title>This blog has moved -- but you don't have to!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_28_this-blog-has-moved-but-you-don-t-have-to/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 02:58:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_28_this-blog-has-moved-but-you-don-t-have-to/</guid><description>In keeping with the project rename we&amp;rsquo;ve moved this blog from it&amp;rsquo;s old home at blog.enzotools.org to its new home at blog.yt-project.org. But, we&amp;rsquo;ve put in a few redirects, and the RSS feed hasn&amp;rsquo;t moved, so you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to do anything different to get here. We&amp;rsquo;ve also enabled anonymous commenting, so feel free to comment below. (But, of course, letting us know who you are would certainly help with keeping in touch!</description></item><item><title>We're now the yt Project!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_26_we-re-now-the-yt-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 08:39:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_26_we-re-now-the-yt-project/</guid><description>This is just a brief blog entry &amp;ndash; other news is on the way soon! &amp;ndash; to let everyone know we&amp;rsquo;ve updated our domains. In keeping with the change in focus of the yt project, expanding to work with multiple codes and take broader views of analysis and visualization, we have moved from enzotools.org to yt-project.org. Some other exciting changes will be coming from this in the future, too!
For more info, see the mailing list announcement.</description></item><item><title>A mission statement and a new homepage!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_24_a-mission-statement-and-a-new-homepage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 18:28:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_24_a-mission-statement-and-a-new-homepage/</guid><description>In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t visited our front page lately, the yt homepage has been redesigned! The old homepage was nice and functional, but it tried to cram too much into too small a place. The new homepage focuses on the three main questions people have when they go to the yt page: &amp;lsquo;How do I get it?', &amp;lsquo;How do I use it?', and &amp;lsquo;How do I participate?&amp;rsquo;
The new page is focused on some concrete examples, some quantitative analysis, and features a heavy dosage of the yt community &amp;ndash; in fact, the redesign came about through a conversation in IRC, where a few of the core developers were speculating about how best to convey how to participate and how strong a community yt has.</description></item><item><title>yt development - Quad trees, Tickets and more</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_21_yt-development-quad-trees-tickets-and-more/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 20:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_21_yt-development-quad-trees-tickets-and-more/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since the last Development post — but in that time, some pretty fun things have been going on. These are some of the smaller things, but there are bigger things in store which I&amp;rsquo;ll write about next time.
QuadTree Projections For a while, there has been the option to use a QuadTree data structure to conduct projections through a simulation volume. This was accessible through the quad_proj attribute, which respected the same interface as the normal proj interface.</description></item><item><title>yt Logo Contest, and possibly a free mug!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_20_yt-logo-contest-and-possibly-a-free-mug/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 17:46:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_20_yt-logo-contest-and-possibly-a-free-mug/</guid><description>yt is in need of an awesome new logo, which is why we are announcing the first ever new logo contest! So here&amp;rsquo;s the deal:
We&amp;rsquo;ll accept entries for the next two weeks. Let&amp;rsquo;s arbitrarily say Tuesday, May 10th, at 11:59:59 pm EST. If there is more than one entry, we will put it up for a community vote at that time.
Oh, and the most important part &amp;ndash; the winner will get a coffee mug with their new logo front and center!</description></item><item><title>yt development - Treecodes, GUIs, IRC and more!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_18_yt-development-treecodes-guis-irc-and-more/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 06:40:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_18_yt-development-treecodes-guis-irc-and-more/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been nearly a month since the last yt development post; in that time, there&amp;rsquo;s been quite a bit of development in a couple different areas. This is culminating in a 2.1 release, for which Sam Skillman is release manager, sometime in the next few days.
Streamlines and Treecode SamS has spent some time over the last month developing two types of streamline code. The first integrates a series of streamlines over a selection of the domain, which can then be visualizing using the mplot3d package.</description></item><item><title>yt development - External Analysis and Simulation Code Support</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_17_yt-development-external-analysis-and-simulation-code-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 06:17:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_17_yt-development-external-analysis-and-simulation-code-support/</guid><description>This last week was the first full week on BitBucket and so far I think it has been quite successful. The new development process is for most of the core developers to maintain personal forks for experimental changes, or longer term changes, and then to commit directly or merge when bug fixes or features are ready to be integrated. The list of forks is easily visible and each individual fork&amp;rsquo;s divergence from the primary repository can be viewed by clicking on the green arrows.</description></item><item><title>yt development - BitBucket, Task Queues, and Streamlines</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_16_yt-development-bitbucket-task-queues-and-streamlines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 05:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_16_yt-development-bitbucket-task-queues-and-streamlines/</guid><description>The major changes this week came mostly in the form of administrative shifts. However, SamS did some great work I&amp;rsquo;m going to hint at (he&amp;rsquo;ll post a blog entry later) and I started laying the ground work for something I&amp;rsquo;ve been excited about for a while, an MPI-aware task queue.
BitBucket For the last couple months, yt has been struggling under the constraints of the hg server on its hosting plan.</description></item><item><title>yt development - Documentation</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_12_yt-development-documentation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 05:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_12_yt-development-documentation/</guid><description>As a result of progress in my scientific goals, and the application of recent yt developments to them, I did not make many changes or developments in yt this week. When I did work on yt, I primarily spent time re-organizing the documentation and fixing several errors. I have added an &amp;ldquo;installation&amp;rdquo; section, consolidated a few sections, and wrote two new sections on how to make plots and on how to generate derived data products.</description></item><item><title>yt development - star particle rendering, simple merger trees and documentation</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_09_yt-development-star-particle-rendering-simple-merger-trees-and-documentation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 05:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_09_yt-development-star-particle-rendering-simple-merger-trees-and-documentation/</guid><description>This is the first of a new series of &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rsquo;s up with yt&amp;rdquo; blog posts I&amp;rsquo;m going to be writing. By keeping this log, I hope that maybe some things that would otherwise get lost in the version control changesets will get brought to greater light. This covers the time period of the first couple weeks in January.
Star Particle Rendering On the mailing list, the question of adding star particles to a volume rendering was raised.</description></item><item><title>yt has moved to mercurial!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_02_yt-has-moved-to-mercurial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2010 06:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_02_yt-has-moved-to-mercurial/</guid><description>For about a year and a half now, most of the unstable development of yt has occurred inside a mercurial repo. Mercurial is a distributed version control system, not unlike git or bzr, where each checkout brings with it the entire history of the repository and enables full development. Each individual can commit changes to their own repository, while still accepting changes from others. It also makes it much easier to submit patches upstream.</description></item></channel></rss>