<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>meta on yt project blog</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/categories/meta/</link><description>Recent content in meta on yt project blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 22:09:04 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/categories/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Our New Blog</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/fork_blogging/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 22:09:04 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/fork_blogging/</guid><description>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve got a new blog! Here&amp;rsquo;s a post that talks about the changes we&amp;rsquo;ve made and
how we expect to move forward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>yt workshop 2012 - a success!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_40_yt-workshop-2012-a-success/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 09:02:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_40_yt-workshop-2012-a-success/</guid><description>The yt workshop last week in Chicago ( http://yt-project.org/workshop2012/ ) was an enormous success. On behalf of the organizing and technical committees, I&amp;rsquo;d like to specifically thank the FLASH Center, particularly Don Lamb, Mila Kuntu, Carrie Eder, for their hospitality; the venue was outstanding and their hospitality touching. Additionally, we&amp;rsquo;re very grateful to the Adler Planetarium&amp;rsquo;s Doug Roberts and Mark SubbaRao for hosting us on Wednesday evening &amp;ndash; seeing the planetarium show as well as volume renderings made by yt users up on the dome was so much fun.</description></item><item><title>Google+ Page for yt</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_35_google-page-for-yt/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 03:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_35_google-page-for-yt/</guid><description>yt now has a Google Plus page. Here&amp;rsquo;s we&amp;rsquo;ll post smaller, less blog-worthy items, hold video conferencing &amp;lsquo;hangouts&amp;rsquo;, and so on. Encircle away! And if you post something you&amp;rsquo;d like to be reshared, just be sure to explicitly share it with &amp;lsquo;+yt&amp;rsquo; so we know.</description></item><item><title>Announcing the 2012 yt Workshop</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_33_announcing-the-2012-yt-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 17:24:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_33_announcing-the-2012-yt-workshop/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to announce the 2012 yt Workshop at the FLASH Center in Chicago, January 24-26.
The workshop will be aimed at both users and developers of yt. We will begin with intensive user training, moving from basic usage to advanced and parallel usage. Users are encouraged to bring their ideas and prototypes for new analysis routines as there will be opportunities to work with more experienced developers. We will then address to how to modify, extend and contribute to yt, and transition to a developers workshop.</description></item><item><title>We're now the yt Project!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_26_we-re-now-the-yt-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 08:39:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_26_we-re-now-the-yt-project/</guid><description>This is just a brief blog entry &amp;ndash; other news is on the way soon! &amp;ndash; to let everyone know we&amp;rsquo;ve updated our domains. In keeping with the change in focus of the yt project, expanding to work with multiple codes and take broader views of analysis and visualization, we have moved from enzotools.org to yt-project.org. Some other exciting changes will be coming from this in the future, too!
For more info, see the mailing list announcement.</description></item><item><title>A mission statement and a new homepage!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_24_a-mission-statement-and-a-new-homepage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 18:28:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_24_a-mission-statement-and-a-new-homepage/</guid><description>In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t visited our front page lately, the yt homepage has been redesigned! The old homepage was nice and functional, but it tried to cram too much into too small a place. The new homepage focuses on the three main questions people have when they go to the yt page: &amp;lsquo;How do I get it?', &amp;lsquo;How do I use it?', and &amp;lsquo;How do I participate?&amp;rsquo;
The new page is focused on some concrete examples, some quantitative analysis, and features a heavy dosage of the yt community &amp;ndash; in fact, the redesign came about through a conversation in IRC, where a few of the core developers were speculating about how best to convey how to participate and how strong a community yt has.</description></item></channel></rss>