<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>yt 2.x on yt project blog</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/tags/yt-2.x/</link><description>Recent content in yt 2.x on yt project blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 16:46:16 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/tags/yt-2.x/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>yt 2.5 released!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/yt-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 16:46:16 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/yt-25/</guid><description>&lt;p>Announcing yt 2.5!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>yt 2.4 released!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_43_yt-2-4-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 02:43:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_43_yt-2-4-released/</guid><description>We’re proud to announce the release of version 2.4 of the yt Project, http://yt-project.org/ . The new version includes many new features, refinements of existing features and numerous bugfixes. We encourage all users to upgrade to take advantage of the changes.
yt is a community-developed analysis and visualization toolkit, primarily directed at astrophysical hydrodynamics simulations. It provides full support for output from the Enzo, FLASH, Orion, and Nyx codes, with preliminary support for several others.</description></item><item><title>yt Version 2.3 Announcement</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_38_yt-version-2-3-announcement/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 10:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_38_yt-version-2-3-announcement/</guid><description>Just in time for the New Year, we’re happy to announce the release of yt version 2.3! ( http://yt-project.org/ ) The new version includes many new modules and enhancements, and the usual set of bug fixes over the last point release. We encourage all users to upgrade to take advantage of the changes.
yt is a community-developed analysis and visualization toolkit for astrophysical simulation data. yt provides full support for Enzo, Orion, Nyx, and FLASH codes, with preliminary support for the RAMSES code (and a handful of others.</description></item><item><title>yt-2.2 Release Announcement</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_29_yt-2-2-release-announcement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 06:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_29_yt-2-2-release-announcement/</guid><description>(Please feel encouraged to forward this message to any other interested parties.)
We are proud to announce the release of yt version 2.2. This release includes several new features, bug fixes, and numerous improvements to the code base and documentation. At the new yt homepage, http://yt-project.org/ , an installation script, a cookbook, documentation and a guide to getting involved can be found. We are particularly proud of the new GUI, entitled &amp;ldquo;Reason,&amp;rdquo; which allows real-time exploration of datasets, and which can be used (locally or remotely over SSH) with no dependencies other than a web browser.</description></item><item><title>yt 2.1 Release Announcement</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_19_yt-2-1-release-announcement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 04:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_19_yt-2-1-release-announcement/</guid><description>We are proud to announce the release of yt version 2.1. This release includes several new features, bug fixes, and numerous improvements to the code base and documentation. At the yt homepage, http://yt.enzotools.org/ , an installation script, a cookbook, documentation and a guide to getting involved can be found.
yt is an analysis and visualization toolkit for Adaptive Mesh Refinement data. yt provides full support for Enzo, Orion, and FLASH codes, with preliminary support for RAMSES, ART, Chombo, CASTRO and MAESTRO codes.</description></item><item><title>yt development - Treecodes, GUIs, IRC and more!</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_18_yt-development-treecodes-guis-irc-and-more/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 06:40:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_18_yt-development-treecodes-guis-irc-and-more/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been nearly a month since the last yt development post; in that time, there&amp;rsquo;s been quite a bit of development in a couple different areas. This is culminating in a 2.1 release, for which Sam Skillman is release manager, sometime in the next few days.
Streamlines and Treecode SamS has spent some time over the last month developing two types of streamline code. The first integrates a series of streamlines over a selection of the domain, which can then be visualizing using the mplot3d package.</description></item><item><title>yt development - 2.0, Cython, and physics module wrapping</title><link>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_10_yt-development-2-0-cython-and-physics-module-wrapping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 07:10:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://munkm.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_10_yt-development-2-0-cython-and-physics-module-wrapping/</guid><description>This is the second blog entry in the weekly series, with some updates on what took place last week with respect to yt development. One of the more exciting things is the final one, which is the start of what I want to focus on for the next couple months or years: integration of physics modules with analysis code, and then the ultimate inversion of that relationship.
yt-2.0 This week saw the release of yt 2.</description></item></channel></rss>