<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>streamlines on yt project blog</title><link>https://yt-project.github.io/yt-blog/tags/streamlines/</link><description>Recent content in streamlines on yt project blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 06:40:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yt-project.github.io/yt-blog/tags/streamlines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>yt development - Treecodes, GUIs, IRC and more!</title><link>https://yt-project.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_18_yt-development-treecodes-guis-irc-and-more/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 06:40:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yt-project.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_18_yt-development-treecodes-guis-irc-and-more/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been nearly a month since the last yt development post; in that time, there&amp;rsquo;s been quite a bit of development in a couple different areas. This is culminating in a 2.1 release, for which Sam Skillman is release manager, sometime in the next few days.
Streamlines and Treecode SamS has spent some time over the last month developing two types of streamline code. The first integrates a series of streamlines over a selection of the domain, which can then be visualizing using the mplot3d package.</description></item><item><title>yt development - BitBucket, Task Queues, and Streamlines</title><link>https://yt-project.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_16_yt-development-bitbucket-task-queues-and-streamlines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 05:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yt-project.github.io/yt-blog/posts/post_16_yt-development-bitbucket-task-queues-and-streamlines/</guid><description>The major changes this week came mostly in the form of administrative shifts. However, SamS did some great work I&amp;rsquo;m going to hint at (he&amp;rsquo;ll post a blog entry later) and I started laying the ground work for something I&amp;rsquo;ve been excited about for a while, an MPI-aware task queue.
BitBucket For the last couple months, yt has been struggling under the constraints of the hg server on its hosting plan.</description></item></channel></rss>